Have you packed all your stuff, uncle?
Packed everything that should be packed
Just take some clothes. It's just a few days
Has aunt finished packing, uncle?
She's finished
She packed her clothes. We can go together then
How can she go? Gotta look after the small animals (chickens and ducks)
Is Xiao Fen going?
The kid (Tian Tian) needs to go to school. She needs to look after the kid
Have you flown before, uncle?
No. Always been farming at home. Never had the time
Flight tickets were so expensive before
It's cheap now. Even cheaper than bus sometimes
Just 5-6 hundered (to Guangzhou)
- That cheap?
- Yeah
I didn't know
But when riding a plane, there's turbulence sometimes
Turbulence is, sometimes the plane may shake for a few times. Shake harder than cars
Is it safe?
Take it easy. Chinese planes are the safest ones
Safe? good
It about 2 hours from Chengdu (to Guangzhou)
So fast?
Has to be fast. Planes fly
Nice. Two hours with no tortures on the road
It's just a while. Like a smoke break
You can't smoke in planes
So I have to hold it if I want to smoke?
Hold it. It's just an hour or so
Just an hour? I can hold it
I'm fine
Uncle is now 60 years old. It's his first time flying, and he's pretty happy about it
- Is that right, uncle?
- Yes
Flying is pretty happy
Haven't finished cutting the chilis
Still a little to finish
Dad is still carrying bricks here
When can you finish?
By this afternoon
Actually, every time I take uncle for a trip, I'm not taking my parents
In fact, my parents have spent most of their life wandering at other places before
Now they prefer to enjoy the, so called "quiet life" at home
Uncle has been in this home town and countryside for decades
He's always wished trips to different places
So now I'm just taking uncle for a trip and relax
I borrowed this car, uncle
Get onboard
You can put the luggage in the back
OK, yeah
In the rear row
- Wear the seatbelt
- OK
Do I remove this?
Take it around you from over there
(Wear the) seatbelt
Let me recall how to start this car
Neutral gear, release hand brake, step on brake, and step on clutch
All right, now set to neutral gear now
No, first gear, then release the clutch
Move when the car starts to shake
Release the brake when you feel the shake
You don't need to rush
I'm fine. I know how to drive
Uncle
Do you feel scary flying?
Not scary. What to scare?
Planes are the safest
Hehehe
He hasn't flown before
I was a little scared when I flew for the first time
Especially when taking off
It feels special only when taking off and landing
Nothing special otherwise
The airport is quite big
An international airport?
Yeah, international
We've arrived, uncle
OK, OK
Arrived
Now we are visiting my buddy with uncle
We've left two boxes of mooncakes at the security check
We'll pick them up later
We are taking two boxes of mooncakes to my buddy
I'm also bring "Kuan You" ("wide oil")
It's sent via delivery
We can't carry it in a plane
Both of us have got our tickets
We got them from different machines
Couldn't get it here
Chongqing dialect
"Jiao Pa Shou Ruan"
We have the same expression in Sichuan
Yeah
Do we say that?
Yeah, we say that
How about this?
What does "Er Bu Gua Wu" mean?
"Er Bu Gua Wu" means
you are capable of something and incapable of something. That's it
We don't have this expression
We do
How about "Zheng Nan Qi Bei"?
This one?
We say "Zheng Er Ba Jing" instead
("Real Serious")
Hm
"Ba Shi"
No need to explain
It's just "nice". "Ba Shi to death"
This one, "Ke Shui Mi Xi"
Do we say that in Sichuan?
We do
We say "Zhuai Ke Da Shui" (Being sleepy)
Yeah
"Che Pu Han" means to snore
Everyone says that
What does "Da Wang Guang" mean?
We don't say that in Sichuan
It's explained below, "not listening carefully"
Every Sichuanese knows about "Che Ba Zi" ("to lie")
All right, let's go to the waiting area
OK
Is this the seat number?
Row 53
Move inside
It's ascending
How do you feel?
No special feeling
The roads below are like chicken intestine
Look like threads
Hehe, because we are high above. So they look small
How do you feel about your first flight?
Not much feeling
Look at this wing. It's swinging
A little bit nervous
A little bit nervous?
No feeling if it's stable
Look at the river below
Such a big river
Look at the cloud. So white
Like a marshmallow
Like cotton
So beautiful
Yeah
"Far in the sky, right under my nose"
Hmm
Wow, uncle you are good. Educated, huh?
Hehe
It's still pretty good living in this society
We can sit in a plane and watch the world outside. So nice
Look at the outside. So beautiful
Looking down from the plane. It's so beautiful below
The cloud below looks like cotton. So nice
So goodlooking
I can also see "electric windmill" spining
That's not an electric fan
That's the engine
Is it for generating electricity?
No. That's the engine of the plane
Look at the cloud
Does it look like a boundless sea
Can't see the bound
The plane is so stable
No up and down
So stable. The water bottle doesn't move at all
I'll also take you in my next trip
Great
We don't have a long trip in the plane
Two hours are still not long enough?
Good enough if we fly to New Zealand
That's good enough
Hehehe
So you want a longer flight
Hahaha
It's not a bad life experience for me
Now I've taken modern plane and hi-speed rail
Not a bad one
Now let's eat
OK, let's eat
A pack of "Zha Cai" (a kind of pickled mustard stem)
A piece of bread
And some fruit
Take your time, uncle
Not too bad
No meat in the plane?
Huh, a little bit of meat
Nice
When we arrive, we'll have bamboo rats to eat
That's also meat
Good, good
There's still meat here
Just deal with it for now
Just a little bit. Meaning it's non-vegetarian
Yeah
Just deal with it for now
OK, OK
All right, I'm also going to eat
That's all for the video
Bye